[Music]
Blessings everyone. This is Chris Kennle
from the rawadvantage.com registered
holistic nutritionist, raw food
lifestyle coach, and raw chef. Today I'm
getting into that second Christmas gift
for you guys, the inside out sushi rolls
or the raaki sushi roll. So, let's get
into it. Baby, I like it. Raw Vantage
likes it raw. Oh, baby, I like it raw.
Yeah, baby, I like it raw.
All right, so here we are again. Sushi,
one of my favorite little raw food
meals. And I hope you guys really
enjoyed that first raw vegan sushi meal.
The best raw vegan sushi out there. If
you haven't checked out that video,
you're going to want to click above or
in the description below. I'll let you
know that all the things I talk about,
all the links are going to be in the
description below. And a lot of people
watch my videos and aren't subscribed.
So, if you're not subscribed yet, go
ahead and just hit that subscribe
button, maybe that bell to be notified
when I have new ones. Like it, make a
comment, all that fun stuff. You know,
it helps everything rise up and me get
out to more people. So, I super super
appreciate that. But I want to let you
guys know that first sushi video is the
one that I would make the most often.
these inside out rolls. They're a little
bit higher on the expertise list and
they use a couple things that uh I
wouldn't necessarily want to do all the
time. So, if you like the other ones, I
would go for those more often. But these
are really fun, fancy, and fun to share
with other people because it's like
what? That's that's raw and how you get
it stuck together and how does it look
all good? And if you don't love the
taste of nori,
it's nice on the inside, you know, then
you don't taste it quite as much cuz
it's not the first thing hitting your
tongue. So, let's get into the recipe.
So, for this recipe, you're going to
need 500 g of cauliflower, 100 g of
fresh ginger, 3 to four teaspoon of
lemon juice or half of a lemon, an 1/th
cup of chia seeds. I prefer the white
chia seeds, some black sesame seeds for
garnish on top. About 75 g of red pepper
or about a half a pepper. Two little
cucumbers or gerkins, about 150 g. one
avocado and four little green onions.
And then of course you're going to need
some raw vegan nori. And if you're not
going to go for the raw vegan nori, then
you can use my better than nori recipe.
The link is below. It's all from Land
Plants. Really dang tasty. It is
actually better than nori. But this is
great. You know, this is a certified
organic vegan raw nori from raw
nori.com. I've used it a bunch of times.
I'm really enjoying it. And uh it's
pretty inexpensive. You know, I I buy
these bags of 50 and use them up. So,
we're going to use four of these. This
recipe is going to make four rolls, you
know, and each roll makes eight pieces.
So, you can, you know, maybe that's for
one person. Maybe that's for two people.
For me, it's definitely one. And
sometimes I even make a little more. But
truthfully, this is pretty darn perfect.
Especially if I started my meal with
fruit. Have a nice juicy fruit meal
first. And then this is my dessert. All
right. So, let's just jump into it. And
as I said, if you haven't watched the
first sushi video, I do recommend
checking that one out. It may go a
little more in depth into preparing some
of the vegetables and stuff like that.
I'm going to breeze through this cuz the
biggest part of this is actually just
the technique and how to actually roll
it and couple extra little tips that go
along with that. But I'm going to still
show it. So, what we're going to do here
is start with the cauliflower just like
we did last time. We're just going to
rinse it off with some clear, clean
water. This here is reverse osmosis.
just want to wash it. Even if it's
organic or not, this is actually a step
that comes into play to make the rice
just a little bit more sticky. So, we're
going to shake off the excess water, but
we're not going to dry this off with a
towel or anything. So, it's still got a
teeny bit of moisture. Now, while that's
sitting here, we have that beautiful
peeled ginger. I love ginger, so I'm
using 100 g of this peeled ginger. I
used a spoon and just rubbed the skin
off of it. And we're going to put this
into the food processor after just a
rough chop. So, we're chopping up the
ginger into medallions.
Place those into the food processor with
the slade
and pulse it up. We're putting this in
first cuz we want to make sure the
ginger is well pulsed. So, here we go.
Sometimes a little bit gets stuck up
here. Push that out and let's give it a
go. Oh yeah. Oh yeah. You may need to
take a trusty spatula, preferably a
kitty spatula.
Get it off the side so that we can make
sure this gets ground up quite nicely.
So what we'll do is we'll put about half
of the cauliflower in here with the
ginger.
Break it into about bite-sized pieces.
It just makes it a little bit easier and
less likely that you'll have huge chunks
of cauliflower left over in the food
processor.
If you don't have a food processor, I
highly recommend checking out Lisa from
Raw Food Romance's wet chop technique.
She actually ends up using a Vitamix
blender and it works really darn well as
well. So, I would recommend checking her
out for that or for any of her recipes
and stuff like that. So, I'll have some
links below so you can check out her wet
chop technique and some of her awesome
recipe books. We're just going to pulse
this up. Again, you want to get it into
like a rough ricelike texture. So,
that's part of the reason we put the
ginger in first so that we don't
overpulse the cauliflower.
I'm going to take this square Pyrex dish
just to put all of this rice, ginger
rice, you can just smell it. It smells
so amazing into it. And you'll
understand why pretty soon. Any bowl
will do, but I find that a nice square
dish makes it even easier. So, use the
spatula, get everything off the edges,
and then we'll continue and make the
rest of the rice.
Let's give it a little bit of a stir to
make sure we mix the ginger and the
cauliflower all evenly. And then we're
going to add the four teaspoon of lemon
juice into the rice just to give a
little bit of that lemony sour vinegary
flavor. We're going to stir that up so
that it coats all the rice and ginger
mixture. And then next, what we're going
to do to get this rice totally ready and
nice and sticky so it actually stays on
the roll and doesn't just fall off is
we're going to add that eighth a cup of
chia seeds. Now, first we're going to
put it in a grinder. So, either a coffee
grinder, your Vitamix blender, or this
is just a little magic bullet with a
seed grinding or grain grinding kind of
attachment. So, we're just going to
pulse that up until it's a nice fed chia
powder. I use white chia seeds. It just
looks a little nicer. You can use any
color.
There we go. So, now it's just a perfect
little chia powder puree. That eighth a
cup really puffed up to almost a/4 cup,
which is pretty awesome. And we'll just
evenly pour this across the entire top
layer. If you want, you could even give
it a little bit of a stir to make it
even better at distributing across all
of the rice mixture.
And you want to be fairly quick cuz
it'll start to stick to individual rice
rice bits. Start stirring that up.
See? Look at that beautiful mix. Oh
yeah.
This just sucks up a little bit of the
moisture and just starts to stick it
together. But another added benefit is
that this really ups the omega-3 fats in
this dish cuz most commonly veggie sushi
rolls have avocado which is it's great
but it is also a lot higher in omega
sixs than threes. And this way you're
really balancing out those omegas which
is better for inflammation and for
long-term EPA and DHA status. So, it's a
little tip and that goes to a little bit
more in depth than this video is really
going to go into, but just makes it more
of a nutritional powerhouse and
wellbalanced fatty acid profile. Plus,
makes it stick better, so it makes the
sushi way better. Stir that up. Make
sure we get every little nook and
cranny, all the corners. Make sure
there's no pockets just of ground chia
seeds in there. Tried some other stuff,
but chia works the absolute best. So,
now that we got this all mixed up and
ready to go, what we're going to do is
press it down. And if you have a handy
dandy little pie scoop, you can do that.
Otherwise, you can use your hand or the
back of a spoon. We're just going to
press that down so it's pretty even. And
then we're just going to take that same
guy or a knife and just divide it into
four. Boom. Even chunks. That's why it's
really nice with this square dish. Then
you can really easily see how much rice
rice goes into each roll. Right. So,
we're going to set this aside
and get all these veggies ready. Now,
we're going to do this really dang quick
because I went way more into it in the
last video and it's really dang simple.
So, here we have two girkens, two little
mini cucumbers. I like using them the
best, but you can use the bigger one.
Essentially, all we're doing is creating
eight little strips with these, or if
you had
or if you had fulls size cucumbers,
you'd make four strips of the same size.
So you have one strip per sushi roll,
but in this case it's two that make up
the one length of the whole sushi roll.
So I'm going to chop off the tips.
Chop off the tips, gobble them directly
into the mouth part,
and then cut it down lengthwise. Turn at
45°.
Cut it in half.
Then we have these four beautiful
sticks. I can do it to the other one.
And that's enough for four rolls. two
pieces each. I do also want to say, you
know, the sky's is the limit. You can
get really fancy with this. You can peel
the cucumbers. You can take out the
seeds if you're using big or long
English cucumbers. You can use grated
carrot or thinly sliced cabbage or
sprouts. So many different fillings. The
purpose of this video isn't to give you
the different fillings. It's to give you
the basic fillings that are used and
then on top of that, you can utilize
this technique to make many different
types of sushi. I am going to let you
know I'm going to be coming out with a
sushi book in the future here. So, it's
going to be going deeper into tons of
different types of rolls and fillings
and ways to do it. So, I hope you guys
enjoy this and more in the future. Got
the red pepper. We're just going to cut
it in half. Cut those in half and cut
those in half. So, we have anywhere from
three to four sticks per roll depending
on the length of the sticks.
So, there's our beautiful red pepper
sticks. Now, last time I used two green
peppers. This time I used four. It's the
same weight. They're just smaller green
peppers. So, last time I used two and I
cut them in half. So, it's half a green
pepper per roll. These are just little
guys. So, it's one each. And I'm going
to chop off most of the white bottom.
Might leave a teeny bit, but chop off
most of that. And I'll save that for a
sauce or for something else. And then
for the avocado, it's super simple.
We're just going to cut it in half.
There we go. Right down the middle.
Twist it. I like to use my teeth.
Take that seed out. And then each of
these you can cut into half. So you get
a quarter per sushi roll. These halves I
then cut into three. So I have three
slices per roll. And then those are all
rip roaring and ready to go. The last
thing, this is an optional ingredient.
You might have saw it at the beginning,
but it's an optional one for the rice
cuz typically an inside out roll has a
little bit of black sesame seeds on top.
So we'll add that as we're rolling them.
All right. So, we're just going to roll
the sushi now. And I'm going to share a
few tricks and tips. So, let's get close
in here. We're going to start with the
shiny side down. And we're going to fill
up about 3/4 of that sushi paper with
the rice.
Going to load the rice up on a cutting
board. On a cutting board that you can
lift. That's one little special trick
that can make this a lot easier. So,
we're going to load up the rice on the
top portion of the nori sheet.
Then, using the trusty pie scoop, we'll
just press that down and distribute it
across the top three quarters. So, you
might have to do a little bit of
shuffling, but eventually you'll get it
nice and even across all of it.
Use the edge of the pie scoop to press
the rice right up to the edge of the
sushi paper.
Get it right up near the top.
Don't be afraid to get your hands in
there to spread it out evenly.
Now, once you got that evenly spread on
top, take your optional black sesame
seeds and sprinkle them all over the
top.
Now, this is where
doing it on the cutting board's really
going to come in handy cuz we're going
to take this covered up sushi mat. Place
it right on top so that the bottom
matches the bottom over here
and carefully
sandwich the two and flip them over.
Then you have the nori upside down on
the sushi mat. So, we're ready to take
the avocado first.
We'll just do three slices.
I usually like to put the biggest ones
on the outside the same way and then the
smaller one on the inside upside down.
Take your cucumber slices and snuggle
those up right beside it. If you need to
munch a little bit off to make them
perfect, that's good.
Take your red peppers and just put them
right on top of there. And your one
spring onion
and put it right there. Now, we're going
to take the nori paper and the mat and
carefully squeeze shut those
ingredients. So, I'm going to try and
get them to be a little bit squished so
that there's no space between them. Nice
and tight. Makes a nice tight sushi
roll. Then lift up and continue rolling,
squeezing every once in a while. Make
sure it's nice and tight. Lift up,
continue rolling. You're going to start
feeling rice. So, we're going to roll
that all the way over until the end
meets the end. And just squeeze it nice
and tight.
And when you unroll, you have a perfect
inside out roll. Now, the next little
trick that you're going to want to do,
take some plastic wrap, preferably
biodegradable,
and place it down right up next to the
sushi, and just carefully roll it right
on. Then, what we can do is
meet that end and start to roll it. And
before you get to the end, fold the one
end over so that you can easily see
where it starts. So you want to get this
as tight as you can. Can remove this.
Get that nice and tight.
And then spin each side so it encases
it. Just like that. And now we have that
perfect looking little sushi roll
encased in there. We'll put it on the
cutting board and carefully cut it in
half. Really sharp knife, nice and
clean.
Make sure you cut through all of the
plastic and cut those in half.
Make sure it's nice and tight. Cut those
in half.
Make sure you cut all the way through
the plastic. And then because of that
little side that we kept, we can just
put it right on the plate and unwrap
these beautiful inside out rolls.
Serving them on the side or you can plop
them up like this and they stay together
really, really well.
That's it, guys. I hope you guys really
found this video useful and helpful and
you have a fun time trying to make some
inside out sushi rolls using these tips
and tricks. If you find this a little
difficult, make the regular rolls.
They're a heck of a lot easier and
they're just as delicious and tasty. So
again, merry Christmas to you guys. I
hope you absolutely love this. Like,
comment, let me know below what you want
to see more videos of and making 2021
the best year yet. Oh, wait. But I got
to try him, right? So, let's take this
guy here. Let's give it a go. I like
them like this. I don't even necessarily
need dipping sauce, but you can use any
dipping sauce you want. You can check
out my naturally rosesome dressings
book. make a whole bunch of different
dressings, you know, and give them a dip
or otherwise just pop them in your
mouth.
You're going to love them. You're going
to love them. Let me know below once you
try them. What do you think? Wishing you
much. Peace. Love and see no fruit.
The best inside out rolls.
Raw vegan sushi food.
Oo. Don't forget to check out my raw
recipes playlist in the top left, the
video just for you in the top right.
Subscribe for more videos in the bottom
right and get your three free ebooks in
the bottom left. Grab your free raw
recipe app available on iPhone and
Android with over 100 free raw recipes,
common fruit and vegetable calorie
breakdown, freaking raw and food combine
chart, shopping cart function, and so
much